biocompare.com 2013-07-05

# Privacy Policy | Biocompare: The Buyer's Guide for Life Scientists

_Effective: 12/26/2012_

CompareNetworks, Inc. is committed to protecting your privacy. We use the information we collect about you to provide you with personalized information, services and tools. We will not share, sell or disclose individually identifiable information to any third party other than as disclosed within this privacy policy. Please read on for more details about our privacy policy. 

CompareNetworks, Inc has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that TRUSTe has reviewed this privacy policy and practices for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. To view a list of the sites owned by CompareNetworks, Inc that are TRUSTe certified please visit www.truste.com. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [info@comparenetworks.com](mailto:info@comparenetworks.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint). 

## Optional Registration 

CompareNetworks, Inc. does not require customers to register. Non-registered users may access all information presented on CompareNetworks, Inc. However, registration does allow customers to personalize and save information. The personal information shared with CompareNetworks, Inc. can be used to help tailor the content we provide on CompareNetworks, Inc. Additionally, CompareNetworks, Inc. may on occasion notify registered users regarding promotions, special offers, updated information, and special features. 

## Registration 

When you register for the site we request certain personally identifiable information from you on the registration form. During registration you are required to give contact information (such as name and e-mail address). We use this information to contact you about the services on our site in which you have expressed interest. 

## Get Quote 

If you are not already registered with the site and wish to obtain a quote for one of the products we offer, we will ask for your name, e-mail address and phone number. We use this information to respond to your inquiry and not for any other purpose. 

## Contact Us 

If you use our contact us forms we will use your name and e-mail address to respond to your inquiry. 

## Communications from the Site 

We will occasionally send you information on products, services, special offers or promotions. You may sign up for these e-mails on our home page. 

Out of respect for your privacy, we present the option not to receive these types of communications. Please see the ÒOpt-OutÓ section below. 

## Newsletters

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter, we will use your e-mail address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you a way to unsubscribe. Please see the Opt-out section below. 

## Opt-out 

If you sign up for our newsletters, special promotion e-mails, and/or services and later change your mind, an unsubscribe option will always be available in our e-mail communications as well as by e-mailing us at [privacy@comparenetworks.com](mailto:privacy@comparenetworks.com). 

## Cookies 

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. 

CompareNetworks, Inc. uses cookies to deliver a better and more personalized service. This cookie is set when you register. The cookie stores an encrypted key that allows the site to access information such as e-mail address, name, and address. Since it is encrypted the cookie itself stores no personal information. 

The use of cookies by our tracking utility company is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access to or control over these cookies. Our tracking utility company uses session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. 

Our third party tracking utility company employs a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that helps us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers' personally identifiable information. 

## IP Addresses 

CompareNetworks, Inc. collects IP addresses for the purposes of system administration, to report aggregate information to our advertisers and to audit the use of our site. When guests request pages from CompareNetworks, Inc. sites, our servers log the guests' IP addresses. We do not normally link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable, which means that a user's session will be logged, but the user remains anonymous to us. 

## Co-Branded Sites

Some pages may have the look and feel of being on one of the CompareNetworks sites, however the information collected on these pages may not be covered under our privacy policy. All information collected on these co-branded pages is owned and controlled by that company's privacy policy. 

At times we may enter into co-branded relationships. When we enter into these types of relationships we will share your name and e-mail address in order for our co-branded partner to fulfill the service you have requested. 

Our privacy policy does not apply to the information collected on these co-branded sites. You should read the privacy policy of our co-branded partner. 

## E-newsletters 

CompareNetworks, Inc. offers free electronic newsletters to users. CompareNetworks, Inc. gathers the e-mail addresses of users who voluntarily subscribe. Users may remove themselves from this mailing list by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email. Users can also subscribe to newsletters at the time of registration. CompareNetworks, Inc. delivers newsletters, marketing and product offerings via e-mail to only registered recipients. The e-mail tracking system recognizes the URL that was clicked, and records some information about you and your computer, such as the e-mail address that you provided to us, the browser, operating system and IP address. 

## Blog/Forums 

If you use a blog or forum on some of our sites, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these blogs and forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these blogs or forums. 

To request removal of your personal information from our blog, contact us at [privacy@comparenetworks.com](mailto:privacy@comparenetworks.com). 

In order to leave comments on some of our pages you can log in to our commenting system by using sign-in services such as Facebook and Twitter Connect. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and e-mail address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network. You also have the option to share your transactions with your friends. If you wish to stop sharing your transactions, you may do so by logging into your account center on these sites and updating your profile 

## Customer Comments/Testimonials 

We post customer comments or testimonials on our sites that may contain personally identifiable information. We do obtain the customer's consent via e-mail prior to posting the comment or testimonial to post their name along with their comment or testimonial.If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [privacy@comparenetworks.com](mailto:privacy@comparenetworks.com). 

## Tell-A-Friend 

If you choose to use our referral service to e-mail a friend an article or blog post from our sites, we will ask you for your friend's name and e-mail address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time e-mail inviting him or her to visit the page you recommended. CompareNetworks stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time e-mail and tracking the success of our referral program. 

Your friend may contact us at [privacy@comparenetworks.com](mailto:privacy@comparenetworks.com) to request that we remove this information from our database. 

## Protecting Your Personal Information 

Your personal information can be password protected. Users should take appropriate measures to protect the secrecy of their password. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personally identifiable information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can e-mail us at [privacy@comparenetworks.com](mailto:privacy@comparenetworks.com). 

## Sharing with Third Parties 

CompareNetworks, Inc. may disclose user information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or if CompareNetworks, Inc. believes that disclosure is necessary to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, the law or with legal process served on CompareNetworks, Inc. Web site or protect and defend the rights or property of CompareNetworks, Inc. or to act in an emergency to protect someone's safety. 

We use other third parties such as a web-hosting platform who hosts the article comment sections of our sites. When you sign up for our site we will share your name, e-mail address and name as necessary for the third party to provide that service. 

CompareNetworks, Inc. may share aggregate data about our users with business partners, advertisers or sponsors. For example, we will say the CompareNetworks, Inc. audience is x percent females and y percent males. But our motivation in doing so is to deliver better content and services to you. CompareNetworks, Inc. may carefully select third parties to send users information regarding their products or services unless the user has opted-out as described above. 

## Contests and Sweepstakes 

CompareNetworks, Inc. offers contests and sweepstakes in which we request certain personal information. At a minimum, the required information includes name and e-mail address; in some cases, the user must answer mandatory survey questions about a range of other personal data. The information gathered in this manner is used to verify the entrant's identity, to send the entrant an e-mail notification that their entry has been received, and to contact winners and/or prize recipients. CompareNetworks, Inc. may divulge this information to a third party, provided the user gives express consent. Conditions which CompareNetworks, Inc. will disclose this information are when a user may expressly choose to receive additional information from the contest sponsor, in which case the user's personally identifiable information is divulged to the advertiser. All information about each contest is clearly posted during the event. All contests and sweepstakes are conducted in full accordance with laws of the United States of America. 

## Updating your Personal Information 

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, or remove it by making the change within the account section of the site or by e-mailing us at [info@comparenetworks.com](mailto:info@comparenetworks.com). 

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer user your information to provide you services contact us at [privacy@comparenetworks.com](mailto:privacy@comparenetworks.com) We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

## Privacy Policy for Children 

CompareNetworks, Inc. is for professionals and usage by children is not intended. The safety of children is very important to us. Children (under age 16) should always ask parents for permission before sending personal information to CompareNetworks, Inc., or to anyone online. 

## Links To Other Sites 

When you are on a CompareNetworks site you could be directed to other sites that are beyond our control. There are links to other sites from CompareNetworks, Inc. pages that take you outside our service. These other sites may send their own cookies to users, collect data or solicit personal information. While CompareNetworks, Inc. strives to protect its users' personal information and privacy, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you disclose online. CompareNetworks, Inc.'s policy does not extend to anything that is inherent in the operation of the Internet, and therefore beyond CompareNetworks, Inc.'s control, and is not to be applied in any manner contrary to applicable law or governmental regulation. 

## Social Media Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button [and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site]. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

## Changes in this Privacy Statement 

If we decide to change our privacy practices, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

**We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we change how we use your personally identifiable information, we will notify you here, by e-mail, or by means of a notice on our home page prior to the change becoming effective.**

## Other 

If you are sharing a computer, others can access your saved information. Another person sharing a computer can set up their own account by simply going to custom settings. 

If you have questions or concerns regarding this privacy statement or other CompareNetworks, Inc. policies, please [contact](mailto:privacy@comparenetworks.com) the company at [privacy@comparenetworks.com](mailto:privacy@comparenetworks.com). 

CompareNetworks Inc.  
395 Oyster Point Blvd  
STE 321  
South San Francisco, CA 94080 

Please see the disclaimer for additional related information.
